Saraba chikyuu yo, tabidatsu fune wa
Farewell Earth, a ship is taking off
Uchuu Senkan Yamato
Space Battleship Yamato
Yamato
A New Voyage
Space Battleship
Ucyuu no kanata Iskandar he unmei seoi ima tobitatsu
It's about to take off to Iscandar carrying the fate of humanity
Kanarazu koko he kaette kuru to
We'll return for sure
Te wo furu hito ni egao de kotae
Smile back at the people waving their hands
Ginga wo hanare Iscandar e harubaru nozomu
Leaving the Milky Way to go all the way to Iscandar
Uchuu Senkan Yamato
Space Battleship Yamato
Unknown large...
Currently, the migration ships are...
I have an emergency transmission
from the home planet Garmillas.
Increase ship speed.
Aye.
No use ! It's too strong !
What is it ?!
Unknown energy ?
It's not the Bolar Federation's...?
The energy from that object is causing
a chain reaction through the crust.
Once it reaches the already-fragile inner core...
If it's not Bolar's, then who...?
More spear-like objects incoming !
Too many to count !
Why ?
Who's doing this, and for what reason ?
President Hiss, please hurry !
This place won't last much longer !
What's going on ?
What will happen to us, Mom ?
Don't worry. We'll be alright.
That's terrible.
Hey, look !
That's Daddy's ship.
Mom, Daddy's ship has arrived !
My dear...
How disgusting of them to target
people who are in the middle of moving !
Let them feel our fangs as
punishment for hurting our planet.
Don't let them get away with this !
All ships, charge !
No matter how strong the body is...
...if we destroy the base...
How was that ?
You good for nothing !
We'll knock all of them down the same way !
But there are too many...
The situation is dire.
No, I mean hopeless.
We don't know what'll happen next.
Today's Your Excellency's date of return.
How could this be happening ?
Hurry and let the remaining
migration ships depart.
Hiss, you too should
join them, before it's too late.
I've heard that you changed.
Looks like the rumors were true…
No, this new you must have
been your true self all along.
Bless the land that gave birth to us.
Long live Desler. Long live Garmillan.
Save as many...
...save as many people of Garmillas as possible.
Such a terrible noise, Daeder.
It's a part of the charm.
Don't underestimate it.
Too much noise will ruin the melody.
It's the sign of a needle jumping.
I'm aware of it, Your Excellency Mœlders.
The recovery operation will be carried out,
without delay, as dictated by the timeline.
All the noise that's not on
the record will be erased.
Great Pleiades, advance !
Uncle...
Uncle !
Too bad we couldn't be a
real father and daughter...
Double-check the rendezvous point.
Father...
Starsha, please have mercy...
Looks like the destruction of the core has begun.
We don't know how it will affect Iscandar.
Please, go to the shelter.
Sister...
Garmillas isn't the target.
Whoever it is, their target is not Garmillas.
Abelt...
Hurry !
We're leaving !
This is it, huh...?
All ships, leave Planet Garmillas
at maximum combat speed !
The Deusula III is descending !
What ?
Führer Desler...
That's ridiculous !
Your Excellency, it's too dangerous.
Still more...
There should still be
many more lives we can save.
Even one more...
Just one more person...
I promised.
I promised to save the planet
and the people of Garmillas.
I did...!
Talan !
If that's so...
If that's so, you must not die here in vain !
Garmillas...Garmillas is...
The planet's doom was preordained…
For that reason,
we kept spilling blood in war.
Everything we fought for...
Everything...
Multiple distress signals received !
The remaining immigration fleet
appears to be landing on Iscandar !
Regroup the fleet. We will...
Iscandar !
Iscandar's left the Salzar System's orbit.
Velocity is 87 and increasing.
Is it because it lost
its twin planet, Garmillas…?
But this speed is...?
Follow...
Follow it !
To all Garmillas people in the universe,
Planet Garmillas is gone.
I repeat. Our home planet...Planet Garmillas is gone.
Excuse me...
Sorry to bother you, but can you take a look at my communications server for Garmillas ?
It's acting odd.
Um..
What's with him ?
That traitor is trying to be friendly, huh ?
It sure is odd for a Garmillas engineer
like Yabu to speak Earth’s language.
Hi...
If you don't mind, I can take a look.
There's a subspace gate between the
Magellanic Cloud and our Milky Way Galaxy.
It's part of the most important infrastructure that supports
the large migration of the Garmillas people to Planet Galman.
A Garmillas patrol fleet is protecting all of
the gates in preparation for a Bolar attack.
Our group will reach the gate in two days.
After completing a ceremony with the Garmillas patrol fleet, and passing through the gate, we'll be in...
The Magellanic Cloud...
One more step, and we'll reach
Garmillas and Iscandar, won't we ?
You're right. It's almost like barging
into someone's yard, though...
That said, Captain Kodai...
Has our fleet matured enough
to stand on its own feet yet ?
Not yet.
They're talented in their own right,
but still inexperienced.
They're educated, but still don't understand the
significance of operating the ship and its weapons.
We still have a lot to teach in order for them to
survive this severe interplanetary circumstance.
The troublemaker, as well ?
Yamato has an uneasy atmosphere, including the situation around the engineer, Yabu.
Could you tell me what you
really think, Captain Kodai ?
What is your true intention of keeping
Domon Ryusuke aboard the Yamato ?
He's like me.
I couldn't acknowledge the death
of my brother a long time ago.
He has the same look in his eyes that
I did when I was testing Captain Okita.
No, his is heavier.
His burden is heavier because he lost
his father in exchange for my life.
I don't think I can prove myself
enough for the sacrifice he made.
As a captain, it might be the right
decision to leave him behind.
Even so, I...
The episode about Kodai and Mori became a
conversation topic among the people of Garmillas.
The people of Earth are impressive for sacrificing the Time Fault to save the lives of two people.
It was just the momentum of the time.
It's called populism.
It was a choice without conviction.
That's why people are scared
of the possibility of another war.
There’s even an outrageous rumor that the
military manipulated the voting results.
Sorry. It's funny that a traitor and a troublemaker
are discussing politics on the Yamato's observation deck.
Forgive me for not being able to help
you solve your communication problem.
It's alright.
I'm glad I can talk to someone like this.
If my father knew that I was on the Yamato,
he'd be so happy that he'd be jumping around.
Once the Time Fault was gone,
a small sub-contractor like ours couldn't survive.
As the company owner, my father wouldn't
vote for the rescue of Captain Kodai.
But what he really wanted would be...
Accident, or suicide…
…even now, we're still not sure.
What's for sure is, he was
exhausted from managing finances.
When I found him, he was still alive.
He looked up at the sky and smiled.
It was the very moment when the Yamato
returned from the higher dimension.
“A hero who saved Earth”…
Be that as it may, bearing my father's death in mind,
the emerging hero appeared to me as a demon.
Why did he smile ?
You'll figure it out.
Oh, sorry. I feel like I can understand
him because of who I am now.
After all, you were with
your father when he…
Hey Domon, this is big !
Planet Garmillas ! Planet Garmillas was...
...destroyed.
The planet was under attack by
an unknown enemy shortly before...
...but it's unclear whether the attack
was related to the planet's destruction.
We don't know if the enemy was
the Bolar Federation or not.
The migration project had just begun, so...
...the majority of the Garmillas people would
have been caught in the planet's destruction...
...most likely.
Most of the migration ships
appear to have been destroyed.
A group of survivors has
landed on Iscandar, but...
Iscandar itself is in big trouble because
it has left its orbit, moving out of control.
The Desler Fleet is in pursuit.
An estimated 100,000 refugees
have landed on Iscandar.
We have no idea what kind
of natural disasters are happening.
I doubt the Desler Fleet alone can save them.
How could this be...?
Right around there,
that was our home planet.
Even though it was dying, how could
it go before me ? Don't you think so ?
We don't know why,
but Iscandar is still accelerating.
At this rate, I can't imagine
how the surface will deteriorate.
I implore you to open the entrance
to Sanktel, beneath the royal capital.
That's the only way to save
100,000 Garmillas refugees...
No.
I can't allow you to do that.
It's a sanctuary reserved for royalty.
We cannot accept strangers who
have not undergone the ritual.
Ritual...?
Iscandar is continuing to accelerate.
Increase our speed !
Don't fall behind !
We're barely keeping up
at maximum combat speed !
It didn't just leave orbit.
There must be something ahead.
What is it ?
Multiple Geshtam signatures detected !
Eliminate the noise.
Who are they ?
I see.
They're the owners of those spears.
If so...
Don't be afraid !
Unlike the spears, we can shoot them down !
Fan out, Berger !
They're the enemy who
destroyed Planet Garmillas.
Don't let even one ship escape !
Annihilate them !
Situation prediction, 0.06.
Begin corrective action and share with all ships.
The needle jumped, didn't it, Daeder ?
It's within the margin of fluctuation.
Then, let's get back to the original timeline.
It can't be.
A planet was forced to...
...Geshtam jump ?!
The Last Day of Garmillas
Episode 3
Save Iscandar! Rebellion of the Young Heroes!!
Next Time
Behind the sorrow...
kanashimi no ushiro de itsumo
Susumu Kodai:
Yuki Mori:
Daisuke Shima:
Ryusuke Domon:
Shigeru Sakamoto:
Kaoru Niimi:
Osamu Yamanami:
Daisuke Ono
Houko Kuwashima
Kenichi Suzumura
Tasuku Hatanaka
Kento Ito
Aya Hisakawa
Masashi Ebara
Abelt Desler:
Fomt Berger:
Gadel Talan:
Wolf Flaken:
Gol Heini:
Melda Dietz:
Yarb Skerge:
Ledof Hiss:
Hilde Shultz:
Vance Baren:
Koichi Yamadera
Junichi Suwabe
Kotaro Yakamura
Akimitsu Takase
Setsuji Sato
Shizuka Ito
Cho
Yosuke Akimono
Ayano Miura
Shinya Fukumatsu
...happiness is always waiting for you
tsugi wa shiawase ga matteiru
Starsha:
Yurisha:
Mœlders:
Daeder:
Balna Skerge:
Oddo Skerge:
Leeza Skerge:
Yu Kishida:
Fumihiko Sano:
Garmillas Officer A:
Garmillas Officer B:
Kikuko Inoue
Houko Kuwashima
Takaya Kuroda
Masuo Amada
Mie Nonozaki
Tomo Muranaka
Chitose Morinaga
Hiroshi Karasuda
Kiyohito Yoshikai
Takahiro Ayase
Keisuke Hamaoka
Let's turn that fairy tale into truth
sonna guuwa wo shinjitsuni kaemashou
You whisper with a spark in your eye
anata no me ga mabushisouni sasayaku
You don’t dream to get hurt
yume wo miru no wa kizutsuku tame janai
Love still shines even now
ai wa ima mo hikari
There’s only one prayer
tada hitotsu no inori
The future has already begun
mirai wa mou hajimatte iru